[希腊北部]
粮草供应的数字呢？
Where are the grain provisioning figures?
这肯定不对
This can't be right.
我已经和他们谈过了
I've been talking with the men.
他们没想到希腊有这么大
They had no idea Greece was so large.
你让我们没完没了地行军 他们已经受不了了
And they're sick of the endless marching you put us through.
我在思考我们的复仇计划
We were plotting our revenge.
我们得找到充足的理由
We must find good ground.
当你了解他们之后 你会发现他们非常亲切 真的
They're quite an amiable lot, really, when you get to know them.
一群贪婪的大肚子人渣
Ravening potbellied whore scum.
希望他们作战也像他们吃一样
Let's hope they fight as well as they eat.
如果你只顾着看粮草官的账目
If you will bury your nose in quartermaster's accounts,
一定不会有好心情的
you must expect to be gloomy.
抬起头来 卡西乌斯 看看周围
Look up, Cassius. Look around.
壮观吗？
Is it not wonderful?
我只看到十万张要吃饭的嘴
I see only 100,000 mouths to feed.
你骨子里一点诗意也没有 卡西乌斯
You have no poetry in you, Cassius.
我们是要与他们一起去拯救共和国
We ride with these men to save the Republic.
是的 对不起 为我的无趣
Yeah, well, sorry to be prosaic,
在我们拯救共和国之前 得先把屋大维打败
before we do any saving of republics, we have Octavian to defeat.
的确 架
Indeed.
如果这次我们得手
If we play this right,
会让布鲁图斯和卡西乌斯大吃一惊
we can take Brutus and Cassius by surprise.
他们会认为对手只是你和你的军队
They will be expecting to face only you and your troops.
所以当我们两支军队到达希腊时 他们就麻烦了
So when both our armies arrive in Greece they will be trapped.
而且他们也没有时间逃跑
And there will be no time for them to flee.
你懂我在说什么吗？要不我讲慢点
Do you understand what I'm saying, or shall I speak more slowly?
不用 利用战略突击是明摆着的
No, making use of strategic surprise is obvious.
这是一份布鲁图斯和卡西乌斯
To that end, there is a list of the most prominent friends
在罗马最忠实的朋友和支持者的名单
and supporters of Brutus and Cassius left in Rome.
我们必须在他们知道我们的意图之前
We should kill them
干掉他们
before they learn what we're about.
你真是个凶残 阴损的家伙
You are a ferocious little cunt...
杀人不见血
with a pen.
他们都是罗马的精英
These are among the finest men in Rome,
有些是我要好的朋友
some of them my good friends.
他们的钱也会派上用场
Their money will be useful as well.
安东尼将军 告诉他们
General Antony, tell them.
西塞罗这个杂种是他们之中最聪明的
Cicero is the cleverest bastard of them all
并且他有最大的间谍网络 他必须第一个死
and he has the largest network of spies. He must die first.
我想添加一两个名字
There are one or two names I'd like to add myself.
我必须回罗马
I shall start back to Rome.
我要召集我的军队并告诉他们
I'll muster my troops and let it be known I intend to go east
我要独自去东方和布鲁图斯与卡西乌斯作战
to confront Brutus and Cassius alone.
莱彼德斯 你要带领一支小部队留在后方
Lepidus, you will remain behind with a small force.
在我们走后 维持罗马的和平
Keep the peace in Rome after we've left.
我同意
I'm pledged to agree with you.
但是我必须说 这些杀戮…
But I must say, these killings...
将这份名单直接交给在艾文台社团的卢西尔斯·乌瑞纳斯
Send the list ahead to Lucius Vorenus at the Aventine Collegium.
命令他按照名单 把活分配下去
Add instructions telling him to divide the names among the gangs.
我有一个人要加上
I have a name while you're at it.
赛维莉娅不行 我们不能杀女人
Not Servilia. We cannot kill women.
不是赛维莉娅
Not Servilia.
- 鲁弗斯·特兰克维鲁斯 - 谁？
- Rufus Tranquillus. - Who?
就是那个奥克塔维娅的朋友伊俄卡斯特她爹？
Isn't he father to Octavia's friend Jocasta?
为什么要他死？
Why do you want him dead?
我不喜欢那个女孩 她对人有坏影响
I don't like the girl. She's a bad influence.
这不是游戏 妈妈
This is not a game, Mother.
她的父亲可是个“巨富”
Her father is immensely rich.
的确 采石场
True. Stone quarries.
那么为鲁弗斯·特兰克维鲁斯默哀吧
Woe unto Rufus Tranquillus, then.
一定要让乌瑞纳斯和保罗
Make sure Vorenus knows that he and Titus Pullo
来亲自处置西塞罗
should deal with Cicero personally.
没问题
All right.
告诉他们
Tell them...
切掉他的双手
to cut off his hands
钉在元老院的大门上
and nail them to the Senate door.
我告诉过这老家伙要是他再跟我作对 我就会这样做
I told the old fool I'd do it if he ever crossed me again.
不能让别人说我食言
Nobody can possibly say that I don't keep my word.
再见 我的心肝 我会想你的
Goodbye, my love. I shall miss you.
我们总是说再见 真是烦人
We're forever saying goodbye. It's becoming tiresome.
在希腊的一场小战役 我们不会再分开了
One little campaign in Greece and we shall never be parted again.
- 你是认真的？- 当然
- Do you mean that? - Of course.
那样我会非常高兴
That would make me very happy.
当你返回时必须带来布鲁图斯的头 作为婚礼的礼物
When you return you must bring me Brutus' head as a wedding present.
是的 婚礼
Yes, a wedding.
是的 我回来的时候是的考虑考虑了
Yes, we must think about that when I return.
现在不要让你的心爱的男孩等待了
Now, don't keep your darling boy waiting.
回罗马的路很长
It's a long way back to Rome.
你要小心屋大维
And you be careful with Octavian.
当然 我知道怎么对付他
Of course. I know how to handle him.
这正是我所担心的
That's what I'm afraid of.
那 看 眼睛好看多了
There, see? Brings out your eyes.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
立刻洗掉
Wash that off at once.
是的 父亲
Yes, Father.
怎么了？一点点红粉而已
What's the problem? A little blush.
你想涂涂你自己
Paint yourself as you wish.
离我女儿远点
You stay away from my daughter.
马修斯 通知几个帮会首领 今天在这开会
Mascius, tell the collegia captains we meet here today.
告诉他们 他们会感兴趣的
Tell them it'll be in their interest to attend.
- 我会的 - 谢谢
- Will do. - Thanks.
一如既往的支持我
Standing up for me like that.
闭嘴 他是头 她是他的女儿
Shut up. He's captain. She's his daughter.
他说了不要给她化妆 就不要再化了
He says don't paint her. Don't fucking paint her.
口气真是一个老三
Spoken like a true third man.
我喜欢你
I like you.
你知道的
You know I do.
但当心 奴隶
But be careful, slave.
我的忍耐是有限度的
I have my limits.
你们每个人都给了名单
Each of you's been given a list.
里面有十个罗马最富有的人
On it are ten of the richest men in Rome.
你们被许可杀了他们
You've been given license to kill them
并拿走你和你的兄弟们能拿走的一切
and are to take of theirs what you and your men can carry.
被谁许可的 你？
Licensed by who, you?
这是屋大维·凯撒的命令
By order of Octavian Caesar.
你有什么权力来决定谁获得什么
What gives you the right to decide who gets what?
这份名单被平均的分配了 大家很公平
The list has been equally divided. You all get your fair share.
我只分到了两个议员
I've only got two senators.
- 不要让他弄脏了 - 我会的 父亲
- Try to keep him out of the mud. - I will, Father.
- 库塔分了六个 - 对
- Cotta here's got six. - Right!
你分到了更多的特权市民 这公平了
You got more equestrians. It balances out.
这是原则
It's the principle!
原则？什么原则？
Principle? What principle?
卢修斯 卢修斯 立刻停下来
Lucius, Lucius, stop right now.
卢修斯 别走泥地 卢修斯
Lucius, get out of the mud. Lucius!
卢修斯 立刻停下来 我发誓我会狠狠的揍你
Lucius, stop right now. I swear I'll smack you so hard.
卢修斯 停下来 停下来
Lucius, stop! Stop it!
就是那一个
That's the one.
卢修斯
Lucius!
对不起 女士 这条路是到…
Excuse me, lady. Is this the way to the temple of...
喂 喂 你不跟她说话
You don't talk.
对每个人来说 都不少了
There's more than enough here for everyone.
将近80个最富有的
Close on 80 of the richest,
高贵的贵族 让你来谋杀和抢劫
noblest patricians for you to murder and then rob.
你们哪一个见过这么多钱？
Which of you has ever seen so much money for the taking?
我们怎么处理这么多钱？
What shall we do with all this wealth?
我是认真的 我们怎么花掉这些沾血的钱？
I'm serious. How shall we spend this blood money?
奴隶？美酒？
Slaves? Wine?
男孩们喜欢的妓女？
Whores for the boys?
我们寻思你有好主意
We can assume you have a better idea.
果树女神的节日就要到了
The Feast of Pomona is coming soon.
每一个帮会照例都会分发
It used to be that each collegium would distribute
一些鱼和面包给人们
fish and bread to the people.
为什么?
Why?
作为果树女神的祭品
As an offering to Pomona
并作为对人民友善的表示
and as a gesture of goodwill to the people.
是 但为什么？
Yes, but why?
人们吃了鱼 然后呢？
The people eat fish. Then what?
然后人们就会认为帮会
Then the people will begin to see the collegia
不仅仅是暴力和恐惧的传播者
as more than purveyors of violence and fear.
但是我们就是那样啊
But that is what we are.
过去是不一样了 过去是这样
It used to be different. It used to be,
人们会到帮会来寻求帮助
people would come to the collegia for help,
来找我们断事情
for justice, for money,
为了婚礼或葬礼借钱
for a marriage or a funeral when they needed it,
配额用完时 来借贷额外的谷物
extra grain when the dole was short.
什么 我们要成为谷神的牧师吗？
What, we're gonna be priests of Ceres now?
谢谢你的历史课 但那是过去的事情了
Thank you for the history lesson, but that was the old days.
从那之后除了战争和骚乱没有别的
And nothing but war and turmoil since then.
- 时代变了 兄弟 - 的确 兄弟
- Things change, brother. - They do, brother.
现在变了
They are changing now.
谁赢了希腊谁就赢了罗马
Whoever wins in Greece wins Rome.
- 某种和平就会降临 - 希望如此
- Some kind of peace will follow. - Suppose it does.
和平不是你我这种人的朋友
Peace is no friend to men like us,
我们这种在献血和混乱中发达的人
men that thrive on blood and anarchy.
帮会必须改变 要不然就会灭亡
The collegia must change or they'll die.
或许我们并不想改变
Suppose we don't want to change.
或许我们并不想浪费美好的金钱 在那些乞丐身上
Suppose we don't want to waste good money on fish for beggars.
我不能强迫你们大方
I cannot force any of you to be generous.
但是 艾文台帮会会用鱼和面包 祭祀果树女神
However, the Aventine will be honoring Pomona with fish and bread.
你们的钱爱怎么花就怎么花吧
You spend your money as you wish.
哦 我懂了 我懂了
Oh, I see. I see!
你装好人 显得我们都是混蛋
Play the big man and make us look bad.
那样 你就不需要我的帮助了
For that, you need no help from me.
乌瑞纳斯 你是正确的 你是正确的
Vorenus, you're right. You're right.
这是个好主意
It's a splendid idea.
我们应当仁慈 大方 让我们哺育人民吧
We shall be charitable. We shall be large. Let us feed the people.
用各种方法 表达我们的善意吧
By all means, goodwill.
那…
So...
兄弟 说吧
speak, brother.
你为什么支持他？
Why'd you back him?
他是个有想法的人 库塔 一个有想法的人
He's a man of vision, Cotta, a man of vision.
作为一名罗马公民 我们有义务支持他
It's our duty as Romans to back him.
- 怎么样了？- 搞定
- And? - It's done.
我不信任那个莫密欧
I don't trust that Memmio.
- 过于圆滑 - 看看再说
- Too smooth by half. - He bears watching.
你来处理西塞罗 嗯？
You'll take care of Cicero?
他在塔斯库勒姆的别墅里
He's at his villa in Tusculum.
他们希望尽快处理掉他
They want it done quick.
- 我马上拿工具出发 - 不要掠夺他了
- I'll get my kit and be off, then. - No looting on this one.
我们应当给他应由的尊重
We'll show some respect.
好的
Right.
要出发了？
Off out, are you?
- 好锋利 - 别碰
- Sharp. - Don't touch that.
- 你去哪？- 不关你事
- Where are you going? - Not your business.
- 客气一点 - 听着 宝贝 我知道你那一套
- Just trying to be friendly. - Look, love, I know your game.
少和我来
I don't want any part of it.
可惜
Too bad.
多美妙的事情啊
It's a good game.
找那些混蛋玩吧
Go find yourself some other fool to play with.
要是你改主意的话…
If you ever change your mind...
别自作多情 我们完了
Don't flatter yourself. We're done.
她想干什么？
What did she want?
哦？没事
Nothing.
- 你了解她 - 是 我了解她
- You know her. - Yes, I know her.
你去哪？
Where are you going?
一点小差事 今天就能完
Bit of work. Only for the day.
你也来吧
Why don't you come along?
我要去漂亮的乡下
It's lovely country where I'm going.
乌瑞纳斯 我们一起去吧
Vorenus, why don't we all go?
别去
Don't go.
我很快就会回来 你都不会觉察到
I'll be back before you know it.
给我留点鸡肉 姑娘们
Save me some of that chicken, girls,
要不我回来就把卢修斯吃了
or I'm eating Lucius when I get back.
- 好运 - 哈 那是我的小名
- Good luck. - It's my middle name.
主人
Dominus.
说 有什么事？
Speak, man, what news?
我刚和安东尼军中的人谈过
I've just spoken to someone in Antony's camp.
然后呢？
And?
说吧 赫克托很可靠
I think your secrets will be safe with Hector. Out with it.
我亲爱的布鲁图斯 我匆忙告诉你一个紧急的消息
"My dear Brutus, I write in haste with urgent news.
屋大维和安东尼和解了
"Octavian and Antony are reconciled.
他们的军队联合了
"Their two armies are united.
他们会在希腊突击你
"They plan to descend on Greece and take you by surprise
他们拥有压倒性的力量
"with an overwhelming force."
主人 杀手已经到门口了
Dominus, armed men are at the door!
你必须在掉进陷阱前退回亚洲
"You must retreat to Asia before the trap is sprung."
- 你得跑了 - 不
- You must run. - No.
太晚了
Too late for that.
你必须以生命保证将信送给布鲁图斯 明白？
On your life, you must get this letter to Brutus. Understand?
- 以生命保证 - 是 先生
- On your life. - Yes, sir.
主人 你要保全性命啊
Master, you must save yourself.
指给他后路
Show him the back way.
快
Be quick!
你就是西塞罗吗？
So are you Cicero, then?
你叫什么名字 年轻人？
What is your name, young man?
泰特斯·波罗 先生
Titus Pullo, sir.
以前是13军团的
Late of the 13th.
啊 那个著名的泰特斯·波罗 荣幸
The famous Titus Pullo. I am honored.
同样 荣幸
Likewise, honored.
谈起著名 每一个人都会首举西塞罗
Talk about famous. Everyone's heard of Cicero.
是啊
Yes.
我猜想
I daresay
你今天的行为会让你不朽
your work today will earn you immortality.
- 什么意思？- 我会被记载在所有的历史书里
- How's that? - I will be in all the history books.
杀我的人 无疑也会被记载
My killer's name, no doubt, will live on also.
阿 我的名字
My name.
我想你说的是我吧
Thought you meant me.
桃子不错
Good peaches.
是 差不多成熟了
Yes, just getting ripe.
我想 这也许不可能
There's no way...
劝阻你不要杀我
I can dissuade you from your task, I suppose?
我有很多钱
I have a great deal of money.
不可能 对不起
No, sorry.
一般而言我容易被收买 但你太重要了
Normally, I'd be tempted, but you're far too important.
想想那后果吧— 我回去没完成任务
Imagine the fuss. I get back and I haven't done my job.
滚开
Go away!
- 离他远点 - 别傻了
- Leave him alone. - Give over.
- 放下你的武器 - 不
- Put your weapon down. - Never.
别捣乱了 我可没有那么多时间
Don't mess about. I haven't got all day.
照他说的做 泰罗
Do as he says, Tyro.
但是 主人
But, Dominus.
听我的 老朋友
Really, old friend,
如果你能看到你是多么可笑
if you could see how absurd you look,
你就不会抵抗了
you would not protest.
照他说的做
Do as he says.
谢谢
Thank you.
不 先别
No, not yet.
请…
Please...
给我几分钟
give me a few moments.
等你准备好了
Whenever you're ready.
我摘些桃子可以吗？
Mind if I pick some peaches?
什么？
What?
欧 可以
Oh, yes...
随便拿
take what you want.
谢谢
Thank you.
给老婆的好礼物
Nice present for the wife.
好了
All right.
动手吧
Now.
别这样了
Stop this at once!
等我死后你再哭
Resume your hideous wailing when I'm gone.
一切都会好的
Everything will be all right.
我赐予你自由了
You've been freed in my will.
照看…
Take...
照看我的人
Take care of my people.
是 主人
Yes, master.
再见
Goodbye.
跪下来容易些
Easiest if you kneel.
你或许不想看到这些
You might not want to watch this.
- 多漂亮的姑娘啊 - 的确
- Such a beautiful girl. - She is.
我无意冒犯
I mean no disrespect,
她永远都不会嫁人 实在是太可惜了
but it seems a shame she'll never have a family of her own.
是啊 是很可惜
It is. It is a shame.
但她可以…
But she could...
嫁人 如果你愿意的话
marry, if you would let her.
我知道内奥比也愿意
I know Niobe would want it so.
内奥比只愿意让她嫁给体面人
Niobe would only want her married to a decent man.
没有体面人愿意娶她
And no decent man would have her.
我们可以试着找找
We might try and find her one.
什么样的男人会娶妓女？
What kind of man would marry a prostitute?
配得上她的男人都不会
No man that she deserves.
- 卢西尔斯 快停下 - 如果她嫁不了好男人…
- Lucius, stop! - If she can't have a good man...
- 卢西尔斯 - 看好你的小崽子 你这农民
- Lucius - Take better care of your brats, peasant.
- 我差点踩死他 - 你这蠢猪 是你骑得太快了
- I could have killed him! - You stupid bastard, you were riding too fast.
你们这些杂种 快给我滚开
Fuck you and your fucking mongrels. Get out of my way.
乌瑞纳斯 别…
Vorenus, no!
孩子们看着呢
The children.
滚
Go.
给我滚远点
Go, get out of my sight.
回去接着玩 还有你 别再靠近这条路
Get back to your game. And, you, stay out of this road.
有谁要桃子？
Anyone want some peaches?
- 美好的一天 不是吗？- 是很好 你呢？
- Good day, was it? - Very nice. Yours?
没问题
No problem.
他人还不坏 那个西赛罗
He's not a bad fellow, that Cicero.
没有拖泥带水 跟你想的不一样
Not stuck up, like you might think.
给你姐姐一个
Give one to your sister.
马克·安东尼又拿来了更多名单
More names from Mark Antony.
- 还有？- 安东尼的敌人很多
- More? - Antony has many enemies.
要全部记起来得花点时间
It takes time to remember them all.
我们已经杀得够多了
Surely we have killed enough.
差不多有1000人
Close on a thousand men.
部队需要支付酬劳 我们总得从什么地方弄到钱的
The troops need paying. We have to get the money from somewhere.
阿格里帕说得有道理 我们下手的速度得放慢一点
Agrippa has a point. We should proceed more slowly.
我们可不愿被…
We do not want to...
看成屠夫
appear butchers.
当然不
Certainly not.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我需要点新鲜空气
I need some air.
- 漫长的一天 - 确实是
- Long day? - Very long.
我猜 这工作让人疲倦
It's tiring work, I imagine,
杀人越货 甚至连无力反抗的人也不放过
killing people, even defenseless ones.
大部分的人我们会让他们自行逃命
Most of them we shall let escape into exile.
他们损失的只有钱财与土地
They will only lose money and land.
家财两空？还算不错呢
Just ruined? That's all right, then.
这活儿不怎么让人高兴 可却必须完成
It's not pleasant work, but it's necessary.
为了共和国
For the good of the Republic.
正是
Exactly.
- 请你原谅 - 不 等一下
- If you'd excuse me. - No, wait.
你最近一直在躲我
You've been avoiding me.
- 我认为这样最好 - 为什么？
- I thought it best. - Why?
免得尴尬
To avoid any awkwardness.
尴尬
Awkwardness?
我明白了
I see.
看来我是对的
I was right, then.
怎么会？
How so?
我认为如果你真像你说的那么爱我的话
I think if you did actually love me as you said,
再怎么尴尬你都不会在乎
you wouldn't mind any amount of awkwardness.
不 不 我很高兴能知道真相
No, I'm glad to know the truth.
得了 别玩我了
Please, do not toy with me.
你不应该误解我的真诚
You cannot have mistaken my sincerity.
但你说避免尴尬啊
But to avoid awkwardness?
我不跟你说话 是因为我清楚 对你的感情是没有希望的
I didn't speak to you because I know my feelings for you are hopeless.
这得我说了算 不是吗？
But that's for me to say, isn't it?
不 不是的
No. No, it's not.
我爸爸是个无名小卒
My father was a nobody.
他的爸爸是个奴隶 我连一丁点高贵血统都没有
His father was a slave. I have not a drop of good blood in me.
所以你是白手起家的
So you have risen purely by merit.
这总是值得称赞的
Surely that is commendable, in its way.
你是盖乌斯·屋大维·恺撒的姐姐
You are sister to Gaius Octavian Caesar.
你绝不会嫁给一个 无名小卒的“值得称赞”的儿子
You'll not be married to the commendable son of a nobody.
- 我爱嫁谁嫁谁 - 不
- I'll marry who I like! - No.
不 你做不到
No, you won't.
你会嫁给你弟弟挑选的 某个有前途的贵族
You'll marry some useful nobleman of your brother's choosing.
- 奥克塔维娅… - 让我一个人待会儿
- Octavia... - Just leave me alone.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
这几个月来都一直折磨着自己
I've been torturing myself these last months.
我没办法 我没办法忍受…
I cannot... I cannot bear to...
别…
Don't.
- 哦 你好 奥克塔维娅 - 米西奈斯 我过来见我弟弟
- Hello, Octavia. - Maecenas, I came to see my brother.
我肯定他见到你会很高兴的
I'm sure he'll be very happy to see you.
阿格里帕 我们找不到那些该死的数据
Agrippa, we can't find the wretched blasted figures
有关税收计划的
for the blasted tax projections.
呃 好的
Yes.
又见到你真高兴
Lovely to see you again.
他们要我们拿出来的 可不是一笔小数目
It is no small sum we are asked to give.
有什么能保证我们的钱
What guarantee is there
可以换来我们想要的影响力呢？
that our money buys the influence we seek?
是希律王的手下向我们提出要求的
It is Herod's own agent who makes this request of us.
如果我们的钱能够确保
If our money can ensure
罗马承认他是
that Rome recognizes him as King of Judea,
朱迪亚之王 那希律王可就欠我们一个人情
Herod will be in our debt. He acknowledges this himself.
他自己也清楚这一点 但是他到底准备贿赂谁？
But who exactly does he intend to bribe?
谁又知道下个月罗马又将落入谁的手中？
Who knows who will be master of Rome next month,
更不用说是明年
leave alone next year?
我们绝不会轻易把钱撒出去 除非一切已经尘埃落定
We will not disburse the money until the conflict is settled.
这里怎么变成了这样？
How has it come to this?
这个神圣之地
In this holy place
你们在这里密谋贿赂
you conspire in bribery,
好让那些异教的人偶崇拜者 统治你们自己的族群
so that idolaters can rule over your own people.
- 你以为自己是谁？- 坐下 摩西
- Who do you think you are? - Sit down, Moses.
你们是想让塞琉卡斯王朝统治朱迪亚？
Would you have the Seleucids rule Judea?
还是托勒密王朝？
Or the Ptolemys?
最好是某个我们熟识的统治者 好让我们与之共事
Better one we know, one we can work with.
为什么要让他们来统治？这是我们的土地
Why let any of them rule? This is our land!
你们是舍弃自己同胞的叛徒
You are traitors to your own kind.
愿神宽恕你们所有人
May Ha-Shem have mercy on all of you.
报上你的名字
Name yourselves.
我们是的阿罗德的儿子
We are the sons of Arod,
来自玛拿西家族
from the families of Manasseh.
我们代表着以色列的愤怒
We are the wrath of Israel.
喔 泰维亚
Oh, Tevye.
真高兴能够获得你的支持
What joy it is to have your strength at my side.
我弄不明白 殴打长者们不成问题
I don't get it. Roughing up the elders, no problem.
- 可是做这些事的理由是什么？- 锡安山圣地就是理由
- But where's the point in that? - Zion is the point.
兄弟们 我们是在拯救圣地之国
We're redeeming the Kingdom of Zion.
记住 朋友们 记住我们的身份
Remember, friends. Remember who we are.
我们是被神选中的子民
We are the chosen people.
不是奴隶 不是畜生 是被神选中的子民
Not slaves, not animals. The chosen people.
闪开 闪开
Make way. Make way there!
谢谢
Thank you.
- 所有人今天都有东西吃 - 愿主保佑你 乌瑞纳斯
- Everybody eats today. - Bless you, Vorenus.
看见了吗？
See?
就跟你要求的一样有条不紊
Orderly as you like.
是的 很不错
Yes, very nice.
屋大维今天走？
Octavian leaving today?
- 胜者通吃 你也赞同？- 我赞同
- Winner takes all, you reckon? - I reckon.
真后悔我没能参加
Shame not to be there.
那些岁月已经是过去的事了 兄弟
Those days are behind us, brother.
我们还有别的事要做 无论如何 很快这里就会恢复平静
We've other concerns here. There'll be peace soon, one way or another.
也许是件好事吧
A good thing, I suppose.
不过？
But?
你知道和平时代我会变成什么样
You know how it goes with me in peacetime.
暴力是我唯一明白的生意经
Violence is the only trade I know.
和平降临 帮会转变 就跟你说的一样
Peace comes, and the collegia change, as you say they must,
我就又是无所事事了 不是吗？我会失业
I'll be on my arse again, won't I?
跟那些醉鬼唠叨我的战斗生涯
Jobless, telling war stories to the rest of the drunkards.
不 现在不一样了
No, it's different now.
你跟我 我们可以干一番大事业
You and me, we can do big things here.
你会的
You will.
你会干一番大事业
You'll do big things.
看见你乐呵呵地找到自己的目标 真替你高兴 是啊
It's good to see you so happy and full of purpose again. It is.
可我呢 我不知道
But me, I don't know.
你可是艾文台山的二当家
You're second man in the Aventine.
二当家
Second man.
我都可以看到它刻在我的墓碑上了
I can see it on my tombstone now.
艾文台山的二当家 他施舍了许多鱼
"Second man on the Aventine. He handed out many fish."
- 施舍鱼又不是坏事 - 不不不
- Nothing wrong with handing out fish. - No, no, no.
精明的生意眼光 毫无疑问 可这不是战士该干的活 对吧？
Canny business, no doubt. But it's not soldier's work, is it?
我是个战士
I'm a soldier!
至少我曾经是
Least I used to be.
第二个钟
Second hour.
我们该走了
We should go.
第三个钟
Third hour.
天啊 一定是弄错了
Gods! That can't be right.
- 他们从不出错 - 第三个钟
- They're always right. - Third hour.
瞎眼的龟奴
Blind, bawdy house slave.
从不出错
Always.
这一套你很熟啊
Familiar with the species, are you?
我是个罪孽深重不干净的女子
I'm an unchaste and sinful woman.
- 我以为你喜欢我这一点 - 对不起
- I thought you liked that about me. - I'm sorry.
- 我不该那么大男人 - 不
- I have no right to be possessive. - No.
我就喜欢你这一点
I like that about you.
- 你真的没事？- 我很好
- Are you sure you're all right? - I'll be fine.
等你走了之后 我肯定会没事的
Once you're gone, I'm sure I shall be fine.
我真的要走了 我已经迟到很久了
I really should go. I'm very late.
那就走吧
Then go.
- 我不想把你就这么留下 - 走吧
- I don't want to leave you like this. - Go!
所有人一起 一起 听我说
Everyone together! Together, I say!
屋大维 求求你
Octavian, please.
哪怕是为了我 对安东尼好点
If only for my sake, be good to Antony.
我保证 母亲
I am pledged to it, mother.
他是个自大的混球 我也明白 可他还算个诚实的好人
He's an arrogant shit, but he's a good and honest man.
你需要他
You need him.
- 你们需要彼此 - 我明白 母亲
- You need each other. - I'm aware, Mother.
- 听着 - 部队已经在集结了
- Listen... - Troops are assembling
我们很快就开拔了
on the Field of Mars. We must be away soon.
- 阿格里帕去哪儿了？- 我不知道
- Where is Agrippa? - I don't know.
跟女人们道别 我猜
Saying goodbye to some woman, I expect.
- 啊？- 他可能养着好几个妓女
- Ah - He attends to several whores.
或是某个情妇
Or one lover.
- 我不知道是哪种 - 做安东尼的朋友
- I don't know which. - Be a friend to Antony.
别显得冷冰冰 高人一等 这只会激怒他 只会让所有人不爽
Don't be cold and superior, it will only provoke him. It provokes everybody.
我们都知道你有多聪明 没有人需要一再提醒
We all know how clever you are. No one needs reminding.
好的 母亲
Yes, Mother.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
在这样的大日子刚从妓院的床上爬起来啊
Hot from a brothel bed on such a day?
真为你感到羞耻 阿格里帕
Shame on you, Agrippa.
我想你保证 绝对不是这样
I assure you, nothing of the sort.
我跟你开玩笑的 没事 我们走吧
I'm teasing you. It's fine. We should go.
再见 母亲
Goodbye, Mother.
愿朱诺神后保佑你
Juno bless you.
哦 感谢天主 你还没走
Thank the gods you haven't gone already.
我很抱歉来晚了 女人们的麻烦事…
I'm sorry I'm late. Women's troubles.
必须先到神庙去一趟 那地方吵得不可开交
Had to go to the temple, the place was a madhouse.
- 我真高兴没有跟你错过 - 给我一个吻吧 姐姐
- I'm so glad I didn't miss you. - Give me a kiss, sister.
人们还等着呢
The men are waiting.
前进
Forward!
现在你可以告诉我关于阿格里帕的一切了
So now you can tell me all about Agrippa.
关于他的什么？
Well, what about him?
你们这对小情人发展多久了？
How long have you two been lovers?
没这回事
It's not true.
哦 得了 别跟你妈妈说谎 你知道这套行不通的
Please, don't lie to your mother, you know it's futile.
你怎么知道的？
How did you know?
现在不就知道了
I didn't until now.
你不能…
You mustn't...
你不能告诉屋大维 求你了
You mustn't tell Octavian. Please!
我想这也无伤大雅
It's harmless enough, I suppose.
你跟阿格里帕肯定有理由小心谨慎
Both you and Agrippa have good reason to be discreet.
你们可以尽情享受一下
You may as well enjoy yourself.
谢谢
Thank you.
只要你还没丧失理智
Just as long as you keep your wits about you.
就别想着能远走高飞 有朝一日嫁给他
Don't think you'll marry him someday
- 因为这是不可能的 - 我知道
- because it won't happen. - I know.
但是我爱他 母亲
But I love him, Mother.
我爱他
I love him.
真是柔肠百结啊 我该拿你怎么办呢？
Soft as cheese. What am I gonna do with you?
救命啊
Help me!
天啊 救救我
Gods, help me!
求你们救救我 我求求你们救我
Please help me! I beg you to help me.
伊俄卡斯特 出什么事了？你出什么事了？
Jocasta, what's wrong? What's happened to you?
夜里有人进来
Men came in the night.
我全家都死光了
All my family are dead.
他们杀死了我全家 还把我掳走
They killed them and took me away.
- 他们污辱了我 - 你现在安全了
- They have dishonored me. - You're safe now.
是吗 母亲？我们会保证她的安全
Isn't she, Mother? We'll keep her safe.
是的 我们会保护你
Of course. We'll protect you.
- 嗨 - 嗨
- Hi - Hi
这整个地方都是一股子鱼味 对吧？
Whole place stinks of fish, doesn't it?
我不在乎 有家的味道
I don't mind. Reminds me of home.
哦 对呀
Oh, yeah
闻起来像鱼 是吧 你那块地
Like fish, did they? Your lot?
我都不知道呢
I didn't know that.
我们有一个大湖 很深
We had a big lake. Deep.
有很多鱼
A lot of fish.
拿头盔干什么？
What is the helmet for?
没什么
Nothing.
- 回想一下以前那些日子 如此而已 - 以前的日子
- Just thinking of old days, that's all. - Old days?
不是今天
Not today.
- 士兵们离开了 - 你说我吗？
- Soldiers leaving. - You mean me?
跟着他们一起走？不会的
Leaving with them? No.
不会
No.
我显然是那么想过
Well, it had crossed my mind, obviously.
我跟长官们很熟 是吧
I'm in with the chiefs, aren't I?
如果我现在回去参军
I mean, if I was to go back in now,
我也许可以当首席长矛手 至少 甚至使节也有可能
I'd probably be first spear at least. Legate even.
想想吧 罗马使节的夫人
Think about that, wife of a legate! Talk about respect.
拥有财富与尊重
And money.
也许有钱买下一个湖
Probably buy a lake.
这会是场短促的战斗
It'd be a short campaign.
每个人都这么说
Everyone says so.
冥神他儿子的 我只不过说说而已
Sons of Dis, I was only talking!
又不是有心要让你哭的
No call for blubbery.
我“还”孕了
I'm "preglant".
什么？
What?
我“还”孕了
I'm "preglant"!
- “还”孕了 - 怀孕？
- "Preglant"! - Pregnant?
随便你叫什么
Whatever you call it!
你拿的是什么？
What is that you've got there?
你望着它发呆都一小时了
You've been mooning over it the last hour.
这是我父亲的印章戒指
This is my father's signet ring.
我从母亲那儿拿到的
I received it from my mother.
我记得我还是小孩子的时候 他就戴在手上了
I remember it on his hand when I was a boy.
戴起来很合适
It's a good fit.
长官 探子回报 已经发现敌军
Sir, word from the scouts. The enemy is sighted.
- 终于来了 - 不只是屋大维的军队 长官
- At last! - It's not just Octavian, sir.
马克·安东尼也跟他一起来了
Mark Antony is with him.
- 这不可能 - 已经看到苍鹫旗了
- That's impossible! - The Heron standard was seen.
- 多少军团？- 看起来有19个
- How many legions? - 19, it seems.
对抗我们的14个
To our 14.
那个卑鄙小人见风使舵了
The worm turns.
- 他们距离多远 - 只有一天的路程
- How far away are they? - A day's march.
集合所有人必须立刻拔营
Muster the men. We must break camp
马上撤退
and begin the retreat immediately.
不 等等 停下
No, wait. Stop.
什么也别做 我们绝不撤退
Do nothing. We will not retreat.
- 老朋友 这可是… - 不
- Old friend, this isn't... - No.
不要再逃避了
No more running.
我们明天就在这里迎击他们
We will meet them here tomorrow.
如果我们赢
If we win,
将给我们带来更大的荣耀
all the more glory for us.
如果我们注定要死
And if we are to die,
丧命此地也没什么不好
this is as good a place as any.
现在就听天由命吧
'Tis in the hands of the gods now.
我们还是占上风的
We have the upper ground.
照他说的做
As he says.
[希腊北部　腓力比]
天啊 我完全不记得了
Heavens, I entirely forgot!
- 今天是你的生日 对吧？- 是吗？
- Today is your birthday, isn't it? - Is it?
我想你是对的
I believe you're right.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
抱歉 这儿没蛋糕
Sorry there's no cake.
那就明年 嗯？你可以给我烤个加大的
Next year. You can bake me an extra big one.
我一定不会忘的
I shan't forget.
别加肉桂 那些总让我打喷嚏
No cinnamon. Makes me sneeze.
如果你要撒尿的话
If you need to urinate,
现在正是时候
now would be the time.
我很好 谢谢
I'm fine, thank you.
你确定？
You sure?
那就让我们开始吧
Let us begin, then.
看仔细了 小子
Watch closely, boy.
看看我是怎么开创历史的
This is how history is made.
现在
Now...
让我们来找点乐子
let's have some fun.
前进
Advance!
抱歉 恕我冒昧
Sorry, rude of me.
要把指挥权给你吗？
Would you like the honor?
不不 你放手去做吧
No, no, you do it by all means.
谢谢
Thank you.
前进
Advance!
发生了什么事？你知道吗？
What is happening? Do you know?
完全不知道
No idea.
听我号令 跟我来
On my command, follow me!
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
当你心存疑问时 就进攻
When in doubt, attack!
部队随安东尼前进
Standard on Antony!
去吧
Go.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们俩 跟我来
You two, on me.
- 长官 - 是的 长官
- Sir! - Yes, sir!
长官 安东尼的部队已经突破了防线
Sir, Antony's forces have broken the line.
我们的右翼已被击溃
Our right flank is gone.
停下
Halt!
我们的右翼已经完了
Our right flank is gone.
派预备部队上前
Send in the reserve cohort!
掩护
Testudo!
前进
Forward!
放下来
Down.
卡西乌斯？
Cassius?
发生了什么事？
What happened?
不清楚 说实话
Not sure, to be honest.
这生日糟透了
Hell of a birthday.
别绝望
Don't despair.
- 这一天还没结束呢 - 长官 我们的中央
- The day's not done yet. - Sir, our center is routed.
已经被包围 必须后撤了 我们必须马上后撤
We must fall back. We must fall back immediately.
我明白了 好吧
I see. All right.
来吧 老朋友 我们该走了
Come, old friend, we have to move.
长官 我们必须离开
Sir, we must go.
卡西乌斯？
Cassius?
我们必须离开
We must go.
长官
Sir.
能够指挥你们作战是我的光荣
It has been an honor and a pleasure leading you.
很抱歉没能打得更漂亮些
I am sorry we could not do better.
现在你们得顾自己了
But you must look to yourselves now.
- 留下你们的小命 - 长官…
- Save your skins. - Sir...
给我母亲带去我的祝愿
Give my best to my mother.
告诉她…
Tell her...
告诉她她该知道的事
Tell her something suitable.
部队停下
Cohort, halt!
继续找 把死尸扔到火堆上
Keep searching! Put the dead on the pyre.
深呼吸 小子
Breathe deep, boy.
胜利的味道
The smell of victory.
浓烟 粪便和腐肉的味道
Smoke, shit and rotting flesh.
- 多美妙啊 不是吗？- 有什么要报告的 阿格里帕？
- Beautiful, isn't it? - What report, Agrippa?
卡西乌斯的尸体已经找到 我们还在找布鲁图斯
The body of Cassius has been found. We're still searching for Brutus.
太好了
Excellent.
把他的首级裹在盐袋子里 运回罗马去
Have the head packed in salt for transportation back to Rome.
人们喜欢…
People appreciate...
这种伎俩 我以为
the little touches, I find.